# BHAVYA TYAGI

# COMPUTER SCIENCE STUDENT

## CONTACT

+91 9717528360

btyagi119@gmail.com

https://github.com/Bhavya1912

Ghaziabad, Sahibabad

## SKILLS

Python

Data preprocessing and visualization

Machine learning algorithms

Mathematics and Statistics

## CERTIFICATIONS

<u>Advanced Learning Algorithms</u>, <u>Stanford University</u>

<u>Supervised Machine Learning:</u>
<u>Regression and Classification,</u>
<u>Stanford University</u>

<u>Convolutional Neural Networks,</u> <u>DeepLearning.Al</u>

<u>Decentralized Finance (DeFi)</u> Infrastructure

# LINKS

GitHub For All my Projects

Medium For All my Blogs

Researchgate For All my Research

Contribution

Contribution

## BLOGS

The Future of Protein Designing: How Machine Learning is Revolutionizing Protein Engineering

<u>Unlocking the Potential of Synthetic Data</u> <u>Generation</u>

The Power of Continual Learning: Staying Ahead in Machine Learning

<u>Federated Learning: Revolutionizing</u>
<u>Machine Learning for Decentralized Data</u>

Ensemble Model: A Comprehensive Guide

## PROFILE

Innovative Machine Learning Engineering Student working on application design, testing, and deployment experience in writing code as well as building neural networks through programming languages, Possess an unbridled passion for machine learning with comprehensive knowledge of machine learning concepts and other related technologies.

PS: All my projects are in my GitHub link:)

## WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Machine learning Intern**

iNeuron.ai

Dec 2022-May 2023

- worked on several projects that utilized the Python programming language.
  These projects likely involved developing and implementing various machine
  learning models, such as supervised and unsupervised learning algorithms,
  natural language processing models, computer vision models, or other
  advanced techniques.
- Collaborated with a team of experienced data scientists and engineers to build and test these models and gained valuable experience working with various Python libraries and tools commonly used in the data science and machine learning fields.

#### **Full Stack Intern**

TwoWaits

June 2021- July2021

- worked with a team of experienced developers to build web applications using the MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js) stack.
- Got involved in various aspects of the development process, such as designing
  and implementing user interfaces, writing server-side code using Node.js and
  Express, developing database schema and queries using MongoDB, and
  integrating front-end components using React.

# EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (CSE)

# **Inderprastha Engineering College**

Relevant coursework: Machine Learning ,Data Structures and Algorithms, Database Management Systems, Object-Oriented Programming,

12th Standard

## **SRDAV Dayanand Vihar**

2018-2020

2020-2024

Physics Chemistry Mathematics and Computer Science

# PROJECTS & ALGORITHMS

# Multiple Disease Prediction ML App

Multiple Disease Prediction ML App This is an ML app for predicting the likelihood of three diseases - diabetes, heart disease, and Parkinson's disease - based on a set of input features.

#### **Uber Data Analytics**

project is to perform data analytics on Uber data using various tools and technologies, including GCP Storage, Python, Compute Instance, Mage Data Pipeline Tool, BigQuery, and Looker Studio.

# Algorithmic Trading Algorithm

3 Investing strategy that selects the 50 stocks with the highest price momentum, selects the 50 stocks with the best value metrics and to get an equal-weight version of the index fund.

## Cancer-Prediction-API

Reliable API for cancer prediction, assisting in early detection and improved treatment outcomes through advanced data analysis and machine learning.

## **Yellow Taxi Demand Prediction**

Given previous info about number of pickups in regions, predict the expected number of pickups in the next 10 minute interval

# **Object-Recognition**

This is a deep learning project that demonstrates how to use ResNet50 to perform object recognition on images. ResNet50 is a convolutional neural network architecture that has been trained on a large dataset of images, and is capable of identifying objects in images with high accuracy.